## Charlotte, NC

704-576-5573 edinhurem@gmail.com

# **Edin Hurem, MBA**

An accomplished Financial Crimes expert with more than 5 years of experience in fraud detection, regulatory issues management including Bank Secrecy Act, Anti-Money Laundering, and The Patriot Act. Expert in both high level advisory consultation and tactical hands-on execution. Specialized in following type of financial crime; Wires, ACH, Checks, Cash and debit card fraud. Self-directed, disciplined, subject matter expert in fraud, and experienced candidate with vision and exceptional abilities to build and manage professional teams.

#### **AREAS OF EXPERTISE**

- Financial Crimes
- Anti-Money Laundering (AML)
- Regulatory Compliance Requirements
- Account / Transaction Research
- Bank Secrecy Act (BSA)
- Foreign Asset Control (OFAC)
- PEP Regulations
- Information Security
- Risk Management
- Account Activity Monitoring
- Suspicious Activity Reports (SAR)
- Customer Relationships

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Financial crimes specialist III — Wells Fargo & Co

#### Charlotte, NC/USA, November 2016 - Present

- Performed compliance and investigative tasks dealing with issues concerning documentation and reporting for Suspicious Activity Reports, Customer Due Diligence, Enhanced Due Diligence, and Know Your Customer reporting;
- Use transactional and customer records from external data, publicly available information, along with various internal system resources and applications, to make a risk-based decision on the disposition of referrals related to fraud, money laundering, or other financial crime;
- Identify, research, and analyze financial transactions and referrals which may be complex and include suspicious situations with moderate to high risk;
- Perform detailed analyses to detect transactional and relationship patterns, trends, anomalies, and schemes across multiple businesses/products;
- Adhered to all policies and procedures in stored by Risk and Compliance;
- Oversaw foreign wire transfers under \$5,000,000.00 to mitigate against fraud losses;
- Managed calls from branch partners focusing on real time fraud to detect money laundering, wire/ACH fraud, deposit fraud and account compromise;
- Monitored regulatory issues and followed established guidelines and procedures set forth by internal and external bodies;
- Conducted investigations consistent with procedures, performing account / transaction research as well as extensive, complex investigations;
- Reviewed and researched suspect items and transactions incommensurate with the customer profile / activity and reported suspicious activity;
- Indicated potential money laundering or terrorist financing in collaboration with compliance managers.

#### Financial crimes specialist II — Wells Fargo & Co

#### Charlotte, NC/USA, June 2015 - November 2016

- Reviewed, verified and identified customer transactions to detect and prevent financial crimes activities, policy violations and suspicious situations in order to mitigate and recover losses;
- Monitored and reviewed complex account activity and claims requiring research that involved multiple transaction channels and products;
- Documented research findings and actions on cases to support conclusions on suspicious activity;
- Interacted with internal and external customers who suspected they have fraudulent, mis posted, or unusual activities on their accounts or were experiencing an immediate financial crisis;
- Ensured strict compliance with all regulations and procedures such as integrity of documentation regarding the referrals.

#### Professional Bank Teller — First Bank

## Johnson City, TN/USA, Month 2012 -December 2014

- Protected customers against scams and fraud attempts;
- Processed cash transactions, loan payments, money orders and savings bonds transactions;
- Informed customers of banking products such as credit cards, visas, accounts, online banking, mobile banking, promotions and demand accounts;
- Recognized customers financial needs based on their account history and recommended other services such as financial advising.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **King University**

MBA — 2019

Specialization: Information Systems Management

#### **TRAININGS**

**East Tennessee State University** 

BBA — 2012

Concentration: Economics

#### **MEMBERSHIPS**

External Fraud

Association of Certified Anti-Money Laundering Specialists (CAMS) Wells Fargo Mentoring Program

## FCI-Special Investigations Financial Crimes Operational Support

## **TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES**

- Hogan
- DAT
- VISA Resolve Online for Debit Processing Services
- ADCC-ICCC
- ATM-POS Transaction Search
- ATM Reports
- VERID

- 3VR
- Store Vision Platform (SVP)
- Universal Workstation (UW)
- FASTDATA